# Yin-Chung (Lloyd) Huang

148 Jilin Road, Luzhu District, Taoyuan City 338, Taiwan (R.O.C.) r09623007@ntu.edu.tw • +886-905161023

Website: https://lloydychuang.github.io

#### PROFILE

Passionate graduate student with strong chemistry and statistic backgrounds. Held a specific domain knowledge in soil science and involved in multidisciplinary study including mineralogy, machine learning, and remote sensing. Experienced in seminar presentation and assisted teaching lectures for more than two semesters. Aimed to apply spectroscopy and pedology knowledge to solve biogeochemical problems. The ambition is demonstrated by peer-reviewed publications, distinguished academic performance and extracurricular experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

### National Taiwan University (NTU)

Master of Science in Agricultural Chemistry

(Expected) Taipei, Taiwan GPA 4.29/4.30

Thesis: Characterizing pedogenesis of podzolic soils in subalpine forests using proximal sensing

### **National Taiwan University**

Biological Statistics Program

Completed 20 designated credits, including Advanced Statistics, Applied Linear Algebra, Experimental Design, Artificial Neural Networks, and Spatial Analysis

### **National Taiwan University**

Bachelor of Science in Agricultural Chemistry

GPA 4.24/4.30

Rank 1/55 (summa cum laude)

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Submitted

Huang, Y. C., Chen, Z. S., Hsu, J. Y., Chiu, C. M., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2022). Differentiation of fine-textured podzolic soils controlled by climate and landscape in Taiwan. Geoderma (SCI, IF = 6.114, ranked 6/37 in Soil Science). (manuscript number: GEODER-D-22-00525)

#### Published papers

Huang, Y. C., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2021). Silicon availability in relation to soil properties in Inceptisols on uncultivated lands and paddy fields in Taiwan. Geoderma Regional, 26: e00406. (SCI, IF = 2.807)

### International conference publications

- Huang, Y. C., Huang, C. Y., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2022). Characterization of podzolic soils using digital soil morphometrics in subtropical subalpine forests. Abstract Proceedings of 22<sup>nd</sup> World Congress of Soil Science. International Union of Soil Science. Glasgow, UK. July 31-Aug. 5, 2022. (oral presentation in person; accepted on Feb. 10, 2022)
- Huang, Y. C., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2021). Characterization of podzolic soils using digital morphometrics in a subtropical subalpine forest of Taiwan. Abstract Proceedings of Pedometric Webinar. International Union of Soil Science. June 16-17, 2021. (oral presentation)
- Huang, Y. C., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2019). Silicon availability and its relation to other properties of soils in Taiwan. Abstract Proceedings of 14th International Conference of the East and Southeast Asia Federation of Soil Science Societies (ESAFS). National Taiwan University. Taipei, Taiwan. Nov. 3-8, 2019. (oral presentation)
- Huang, Y. C., Tsui, C. C., Chiang, C. H., & Hseu, Z. Y. (2018). Element composition of the colluvial soils at an archeological site from Linkou Terrace, Taiwan. Abstract Proceedings of Joint Seminar on Environmental Ecology and Restoration. Ishikawa Prefectural University. Hakodate, Japan. Sept. 3-6, 2018. (oral presentation)

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Soil Survey and Remediation Laboratory, NTU

July 2017 – Present

Explored the application of portable X-ray fluorescence and Vis/NIR/SWIR spectroradiometers on elucidating soil genesis process

Sept. 2017 - June 2020

Sept. 2019 – Jan. 2022

Sept. 2020 - July 2022

Taipei, Taiwan

- Investigated the differentiation of podzolic soils in subalpine forests in Taiwan using selective extraction, micromorphology, and multivariate statistics
- Analyzed the distribution of silicon (Si) availability and its difference in forest soils and paddy fields
- Carried out physical and chemical analysis on the soils from an archeological site for the department of Anthropology, NTU

### AWARDS & HONORS

Travel Grants supported by International Union of Soil Sciences (IUSS)

July 2022

Up to 1000 USD as reimbursements of travel costs for early-career scientists

(Accepted May 2022)

- Acquired travel grant to 22<sup>nd</sup> World Congress of Soil Science

**Honorable Mention for Academic Thesis Competition** 

May 2021

**Honorable Mention for Poster Competition** 

Nov. 2020

Annual Meeting of the Chinese Society of Soil and Fertilizer Sciences

**Dean's List Award (Academic Excellence Award)** 

Annual Meeting of the Geography Society of China

Oct. 2020

Top 5% of class in a semester

Oct. & Apr. 2019

- Demonstrated diligence on every subject

Oct. & Apr. 2018

- Completed all credits with outstanding grades

Oct. & Apr. 2017

### **Hsin Tian Kong Long-term Scholarship**

July 2019 – June 2022

1500 USD each semester

- Acquired financial support from the Cultural and Educational Foundation of the largest religious group in Taiwan

### **CONFERENCES EXPERIENCE**

### 22<sup>nd</sup> World Congress of Soil Science

July 31 – Aug. 5, 2022

Oral presentation (accepted on Feb. 10, 2022)

Glasgow, UK

- The leading international conference in soil science with over 3000 participants worldwide
- Topic: Characterization of podzolic soils using digital soil morphometrics in subtropical subalpine forests

Pedometric Webinar June 2021

Oral presentation Virtual

- Webinar held by the Pedometrics commission of the International Union of Soil Sciences (IUSS)
- Topic: Characterization of podzolic soils using digital soil morphometrics in a subtropical subalpine forest of Taiwan

# **Annual Meeting of the Geography Society of China** *Oral presentation*

May 2021

Virtual

- Topic: Characterization of podzolic soils in Shanlinshi using digital soil morphometrics

### Annual Meeting of the Chinese Society of Soil and Fertilizer Sciences

Nov. 2020

Poster presentation

Taichung, Taiwan

- Topic: Using Vis-NIR spectroscopy and pXRF to pedogenesis
- Presented research progress of a collaborative project with the Department of Geology, NTU

# 14<sup>th</sup> Conference of the East and Southeast Asia Federation of Soil Science Societies (ESAFS)

Nov. 2019 Taipei, Taiwan

Oral presentation
Topic: Silicon availability and its relation to other properties of soils in Taiwan

### Joint Seminar on Environmental Ecology and Restoration

Sept. 2018

Oral presentation

Hakodate, Japan

- Joint seminar between NTU and Ishikawa Prefectural University
- Topic: Element composition of the colluvial soils at an archeological site from Linkou terrace, Taiwan
- Presented research progress of a collaborative project with the Department of Anthropology, NTU

### **Computer Programming**

R (4 years) & Python (1 year)

### **Laboratory Instruments**

- Field-portable Vis/NIR/SWIR spectroradiometer (ASD FieldSpec 3)
- Portable X-ray fluorescence spectroscopy (Olympus DELTA Premium pXRF)
- Atomic absorption spectroscopy
- X-ray diffraction

### **English**

- TOEFL: 107 (R30 / L30 / S23 / W24)

- TOEIC: 975

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

### Soil Science Lab (2020, 2021)

Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2021 – Jan. 2022 Sept. 2020 – Jan. 2021

- Organized weekly soil science lab lecture
- Delivered lectures on soil science and statistics

### EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

### **NTU Agricultural Chemistry Workshop**

Director of Academic Department

July 2019 Taipei, Taiwan

- Organized seminar on the topic of "The Merits and Sins of Paraquat"
- Delivered lectures on soil analysis & soil chemistry
- Hosted four invited speeches and one field trip

## New Taipei City Model United Nations (MUN) 2018 Chair

Aug. 2018 Taipei, Taiwan

- Committee: United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)
- Topic: Harnessing SDGs to Achieve Inclusive Growth
- Wrote Background Guide with detailed introduction and explanation of topic
- Presided a committee with over 100 delegates in the largest MUN event in Taiwan

### Overseas Community Affairs Council (OCAC, ROC)

Participator of OCAC Youth Bridge Program

July 2018 London, UK

- Visited Taipei Representative Office (TRO) in the UK
- Discussed with the Representative (Ambassador) on the topic of youth education

# Harvard World Model United Nations (MUN) 2017 Delegate of Iraq

Mar. 2017 Montreal, Canada

- Committee: World Health Organization (WHO)
- Topic: Reforming the Global Pharmaceutical Industry
- Contributed to the Draft Resolution that was adopted by the committee